import { QuizQuestion } from '@/types/quiz';

export const quizQuestions: QuizQuestion[] = [
  // 既存の問題
  {
    id: '1',
    question: 'イネ',
    answer: 'Oryza sativa L.',
    hint: 'Oryza sativa L.',
  },
  {
    id: '2',
    question: 'アメリカイネ',
    answer: 'Oryza glaberrima Steud.',
    hint: 'Oryza glaberrima Steud.',
  },
  {
    id: '3',
    question: 'コムギ',
    answer: 'Triticum aestivum L.',
    hint: 'Triticum aestivum L.',
  },
  {
    id: '4',
    question: 'デュラムコムギ',
    answer: 'Triticum durum Desf.',
    hint: 'Triticum durum Desf.',
  },
  {
    id: '5',
    question: 'オオムギ',
    answer: 'Hordeum vulgare L. emend Lam.',
    hint: 'Hordeum vulgare L. emend Lam.',
  },
  // 追加の問題
  {
    id: '6',
    question: 'ライムギ',
    answer: 'Secale cereale L.',
    hint: 'Secale cereale L.',
  },
  {
    id: '7',
    question: 'エンバク',
    answer: 'Avena sativa L..',
    hint: 'Avena sativa L.',
  },
  {
    id: '8',
    question: 'トウモロコシ',
    answer: 'Zea mays L.',
    hint: 'Zea mays L.',
  },
  {
    id: '9',
    question: 'モロコシ（ソルガム）',
    answer: 'Sorghum bicolor Moench',
    hint: 'Sorghum bicolor Moench',
  },
  {
    id: '10',
    question: 'アワ',
    answer: 'Setaria italica Beauv.',
    hint: 'Setaria italica Beauv.',
  },
  {
    id: '11',
    question: 'キビ',
    answer: 'Panicum miliaceum L.',
    hint: 'Panicum miliaceum L.',
  },
  {
    id: '12',
    question: 'ヒエ',
    answer: 'Echinochloa esculenta Scholz',
    hint: 'Echinochloa esculenta Scholz',
  },
  {
    id: '13',
    question: 'ソバ',
    answer: 'Fagopyrum esculentum Moench',
    hint: 'Fagopyrum esculentum Moench',
  },
  {
    id: '14',
    question: 'インゲンマメ',
    answer: 'Phaseolus vulgaris L.',
    hint: 'Pha vul',
  },
  {
    id: '15',
    question: 'ダイズ（大豆）',
    answer: 'Glycine max Merr.',
    hint: 'Glycine max Merr.',
  },
];